Gerry Mulligan Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Gerry Mulligan Collection circa 1940-1994
ML31.M85
Mulligan, Gerry
Approximately 200,000 items 160 containers 80.0 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Gerry Mulligan (1927-1996) was an American jazz saxophonist, composer, arranger, and bandleader. The collection chiefly consists of scores, sketches, lead sheets, and instrumental parts for original compositions by Mulligan as well as for works by other composers. In many instances, there are multiple versions of Mulligan's best-known works. These music materials include manuscripts, holograph manuscripts, printed items, and reproductions. In addition, the collection includes a small amount of photographs, awards, clippings, programs, realia, song lists for different concerts or projects, and other miscellaneous materials.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Boras, Tom.; Brookmeyer, Bob, 1929-; Cohn, Al.; Dankworth, John.; Forman, Mitchel, 1956-; Grusin, Dave.; Handy, George.; Holman, Bill.; Lee, Julian, 1923-; Mandel, Johnny.; McFarland, Gary.; Mulligan, Gerry--Manuscripts.; Mulligan, Gerry--Photographs.; Mulligan, Gerry.; Mulligan, Gerry.; Mulligan, Gerry. Selections.
Subjects
Arrangers (Musicians)--United States.; Composers--United States.; Jazz musicians--United States.; Jazz--Lead sheets.; Jazz.; Music--Manuscripts--United States.; Saxophonists--United States.
Form/Genre
Artifacts (Object genre); Clippings (Information artifacts); Photographic prints.; Programs (Documents)
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift, Franca Rota Mulligan, 1997 and 2005.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Transfers
Sound and video recordings have been transferred to the Library of Congress Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division.
For more information on the sound recordings, refer to the collection level record in the Library of Congress online catalog http://lccn.loc.gov/98701932.
Access and Restrictions
The Gerry Mulligan Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Online Content
Part of the Gerry Mulligan Collection is available on the Library of Congress Web site at http://memory.loc.gov/diglib/ihas/html/mulligan/mulligan-home.html.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1927, Apr. 6 Born, Gerald Joseph Mulligan, Queens, New York
1934 Began studying piano and clarinet
1941 Mulligan family moved to Reading, Pennsylvania Studied saxophone and clarinet with Sammy Correnti who also encouraged him to study arranging
1943 Mulligan family moved to Philadelphia Contacted Johnny Warrington, director of WCAU-CBS radio orchestra, and began working as an arranger Dropped out of high school and began arranging for Tommy Tucker and pianist Elliot Lawrence
1946 Mulligan's arrangements of "How High the Moon" and "Disc Jockey Jump" are recorded with Gene Krupa, marking Mulligan's first appearance on a recording
1947 Arranged for and performed with the orchestras of Woody Herman and Claude Thornhill Began studies with arranger Gil Evans
1949-1950 Created arrangements for and performed on the Birth of the Cool sessions with Miles Davis The album included original Mulligan compositions "Jeru," (a nickname Davis gave to Mulligan), "Venus de Milo," and "Rocker”
1951 Tentet was formed Mulligan Plays Mulligan, his first recording as a leader, was released containing seven of his original compositions
1952 The first recording of the pianoless Gerry Mulligan Quartet was released. The 78rpm recording Lullaby of the Leaves, with "Bernie's Tune," featured Mulligan, Chet Baker (trumpet), Bob Whitlock (bass), and Chico Hamilton (drums) Wrote and arranged "Young Blood" for Stan Kenton's band
1957 Mulligan Meets Monk was recorded with pianist Thelonious Monk, Wilbur Ware (bass), and Shadow Wilson (drums)
1960 Concert Jazz Band was formed Band appeared at Village Vanguard in New York and featured pianoless rhythm section, five reeds (including Mulligan), and six brass
1965 Mulligan, playing baritone saxophone and clarinet, recorded Feelin' Good with a quintet and ten-piece string section
1968-1972 Toured frequently with Dave Brubeck Appeared as soloist on Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra’s recording of Brubeck’s oratorio, The Light in the Wilderness
1971-1972 Recorded and released The Age of Steam
1974 Met future wife Countess Franca Rota Borghini Baldovinetti Recorded Summit with Astor Piazzolla in Milan
1976 Married Franca Rota Borghini Baldovinetti
1977 Composed score for the French film La Menace
1978 Re-formed Concert Jazz Band for the Newport Jazz Festival Performed at President Jimmy Carter's festival, "Jazz at the White House"
1980 Recorded Walk on the Water
1981 Walk on the Water won Grammy Award for "Best Jazz Instrumental Performance by a Big Band"
1982 Played solo soprano saxophone in Ravel's Bolero with the New York Philharmonic, at Zubin Mehta's invitation
1983 Little Big Horn released on the GRP recording label
1984 Commissioned composer Harry Freedman to write The Sax Chronicles, a work in which Mulligan's melodies were arranged in the styles of Bach, Brahms, and Mozart Completed Entente for Baritone Saxophone and Orchestra, his first composition for symphony orchestra and solo saxophone
1987 Symphonic Dreams, the first recording of Mulligan with a symphony orchestra, was released
1988 Named a "Duke Ellington Fellow" by Yale University
1989 Recorded Lonesome Boulevard
1991 Assembled Gerry Mulligan Tentet for Re-Birth of the Cool
1992 Performed on National Mall in Washington, D.C. in ceremonies celebrating the inauguration of President Bill Clinton
1994 Elected into the Down Beat Hall of Fame
1995 Dragonfly was released Performed at benefit concert with the Tibetan Monks of the Sera Je Monastery in India and Ornella Vanoni at the Teatro Nazionale in Milan, Italy, where he improvised with thirteen monks playing traditional instruments Won Down Beat International Critics and Readers Poll for Baritone Saxophonist of the Year
1996, Jan. 20 Died at his home in Darien, Connecticut
1996, Oct. 19 Wynton Marsalis and the Lincoln Center Jazz Orchestra performed a concert, "Jeru: The Music of Gerry Mulligan," at Lincoln Center
1997 The Gerry Mulligan All-Star Tribute Band, with soloists Bob Brookmeyer, Lee Konitz, and Randy Brecker, gave a concert series at the Blue Note in New York
1999 The Library of Congress Music Division opened an exhibition of materials from the Gerry Mulligan Collection in the James Madison Memorial Building
2004 The Gerry Mulligan Collection, featuring his oral autobiography, was launched as part of the Library of Congress' "Performing Arts Encyclopedia" initiative
Scope and Content Note
The manuscripts in the Gerry Mulligan Collection were processed in a manner that complements the arrangement of the original Gerry Mulligan Music Library.
Mulligan divided his library into sections that reflected specific musical groupings or projects. His categories included: music written for albums; lead sheets and sketches; concert jazz band arrangements and parts; miscellaneous arrangements for different size bands (12 or more/less musicians); small band; symphonic arrangements; song lists for different concerts or projects; and tentet arrangements and parts.
In this finding aid, titles are arranged alphabetically in the container list. Those that appeared in multiple categories in Mulligan's library are consolidated under a single heading for ease of navigation. All titles are original Gerry Mulligan compositions and arrangements unless noted. An index of arrangers found within the collection is provided at the end.
In addition, the collection includes a small amount of photographs, awards, clippings, programs, realia, song lists for different concerts or projects, and other miscellaneous materials.
Organization of the Gerry Mulligan Collection
The Gerry Mulligan Collection is organized into two series:
Music
Miscellany
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006562035
Container List
- Music (Box 1-148, 160)
  - 4 horns
    - Lead sheets (Box-folder 23/12)
  - 17 mile drive
    - Parts (trumpet, bass, drum) (quartet), Incomplete (Box-folder 66/7)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Part (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheets; miscellaneous parts (Box-folder 15/4)
  - 18 carrots
    - Score; parts (Concert Jazz Band), Bill Holman arrangement (Box-folder 120/3)
    - Miscellaneous parts (clarinet, bass) (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Lead sheets (Box-folder 10/5)
  - 1st suite for baritone sax, french horn and woodwind quintet, Alec Wilder
    - Part (baritone sax) (Box-folder 81/4)
  - 2nd suite for baritone sax, french horn and woodwind quintet, Alec Wilder
    - Part (baritone sax) (Box-folder 81/4)
  - Absent friends don't go away
    - Manuscript score (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 129/4)
    - Photocopied score (Concert Jazz Band), Revision, 1991; Incomplete
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 45/4)
    - Part (drums), GM personal performance part (Box-folder 116)
    - Sketches (Box-folder 21/6)
    - List of songs for the Mel Tormé vocal compilation "Tentet with Tormé" (Box-folder 62/5)
    - Lead sheets (tentet), For the Mel Tormé vocal compilation "Tentet with Tormé" (Box-folder 62/6)
  - Across the track blues, Duke Ellington
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Missing trombone 2 part; Tom Fay arrangement (Box-folder 38/2)
    - Parts (baritone saxophone, vibes, piano, guitar, bass, drums) (sextet) (Box-folder 67/3)
    - Lead sheets; sketches (Box-folder 16/7)
  - A-flat etude for John Dankworth
    - Score (big band) (Box-folder 48/4)
  - Afterglow
    - Score; parts (Concert Jazz Band), Tom Boras arrangement (Box-folder 148/4)
  - The age of steam, Materials not used for the recording sessions
    - Lead sheets; sketches, Titles: All in the family; Dearly beloved; Sweet dreams; Beaver 1-3 (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Air for timpani and trumpets
    - Parts (orchestra) (Box-folder 110/6)
  - Aire de Buenos Aires see also No. 1
    - Trumpet part, Title on folder: Small band trumpet parts (Box-folder 66/2)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Lead sheets, GM notes regarding "Rio" in "Brazilian collection" folder (Box-folder 18/8)
  - All about Rosie, George Russell
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 145/8)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 31/4)
  - All is fair
    - Parts, Tune lists with timings and notes; For quintet recording with Gerry Niewood (Box-folder 65/4)
  - All my life
    - Lead sheet with lyrics, For the play/musical Happy Birthday (Box-folder 13/6)
  - All the things you are
    - Score; sketch for introduction, On folder: For Kenton (Box-folder 133/12)
    - Score; sketches, On folder: Record arr. revised, D46B - in pieces (Box-folder 133/13)
    - Parts (big band) (Box-folder 49/5)
  - Along came Betty, Benny Golson
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 8/2)
  - American dream
    - Sketch score (Box-folder 50/3)
    - Parts, GM list notes: unreleased (Box-folder 53/5)
  - Amor em Paz
    - Part (baritone saxophone), For the 1994 recording Paraiso (Box-folder 23/8)
    - Lead sheets with lyrics, For the 1994 recording Paraiso (Box-folder 23/8)
  - And then they lived haphazardly
    - Score; parts (Concert Jazz Band), Roger Kellaway arrangement (Box-folder 119/1)
    - Part (bass), GM personal performance part (Box-folder 116)
  - And you called my name, Benny Golson
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Angelica, Mitch Forman
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Mitch Forman arrangement (Box-folder 145/13)
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Mitch Forman arrangement (Box-folder 13/8)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Mitch Forman arrangement (Box-folder 35/6)
    - Parts (soprano saxophone, bass, piano), GM personal performance parts (Box-folder 116)
    - Part (bass), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
  - Another day like yesterday
    - Lead sheets; song lists (quartet) (Box-folder 23/12)
  - Another kind of Sunday
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Dave Grusin arrangement (Box-folder 125/5)
    - Score; sketches (tentet), Dave Grusin arrangement (Box-folder 138/9)
    - Score; parts (tentet), Dave Grusin arrangement (Box-folder 136/6)
    - Part (baritone saxophone), GM personal performance part (Box-folder 116)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 36/2)
    - Parts (tentet), Incomplete; Dave Grusin arrangement (Box-folder 138/9)
    - Parts (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
  - Ant hill
    - Lead sheets; miscellaneous parts (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Lead sheets, GM notes regarding "Rio" in folder "Brazilian collection" (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Anthem [theme for I'm not Rappaport]
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheets, For the 1995 recording Dragonfly (Box-folder 68/2)
  - Anything but love, baby!
    - Part (alto sax), From "Shorty Rogers" folder (Box-folder 62/2)
  - Apostrophe
    - Lead sheet, Laid in: tentet song list; On folder: 12/30/1991 (Box-folder 62/5)
  - Apple core
    - Score; parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 120/2)
    - Score (sextet), Last four measures only (Box-folder 140/4)
    - Lead sheets (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Apple piety
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 127/7)
    - Score; sketches (Concert Jazz Band), Partial original score, complete copy (Box-folder 127/6)
    - Part (baritone saxophone), GM personal performance parts (Box-folder 116)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 39/4)
  - Are you real, Benny Golson
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Around sundown
    - Parts (baritone saxophone, bass, piano), GM personal performance parts (Box-folder 116)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 41/4)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Trumpet part (quartet) (Box-folder 66/7)
    - Lead sheet (quintet), For quintet recording with Gerry Niewood (Box-folder 65/4)
    - Lead sheets (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Art of trumpet
    - Score; lead sheets; notes (tentet) (Box-folder 139/2)
    - Score; parts, For the 1995 recording Dragonfly (Box-folder 140/12)
    - Score; sketches (tentet) (Box-folder 139/1)
    - Parts; sketches (tentet) (Box-folder 63/2)
    - Parts (tentet) (Box-folder 64/1)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheets; part (trumpet), On folder: Art Farmer, Lincoln Center '94, The art of trumpet (Box-folder 24/1)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 23A/18)
  - As catch can
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Al Cohn arrangement (Box-folder 122/4)
    - Score; parts (bass, piano, trumpet) (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Sketches for horns; score; parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 25/4)
    - Lead sheets; sketches (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Trumpet 1 part is missing; Al Cohn arrangement (Box-folder 33/1)
    - Part (trumpet) (quartet), On folder: Quartet trumpet parts - originals (Box-folder 66/7)
    - Parts (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
  - Astaire Show
    - Lead sheets with lyrics, Titles: Isn't this a lovely day; I used to be color blind; I've got my eyes on you; I'm building up to an awful let-down; Let yourself go; Things are looking up (Box-folder 53/2)
  - At sunrise
    - Lead sheets; sketches, On folder: New quartet, 6/24/94 (Box-folder 23A/1)
  - Auld lang syne
    - Score, John Bambridge arrangement; For Cincinnatti Pops concert (Box-folder 148/6)
  - Autumn leaves, Joseph Kosma
    - Part (alto or baritone saxophone), From "Standards" folder (Box-folder 18/19)
  - B C blues
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement (Box-folder 67/5)
  - Baby grand
    - Parts (sextet), On folder: Sextet - 4 horn scores by Jeffy Hurwitz (Box-folder 140/2)
  - Bach theme
    - Part (baritone saxophone) (orchestra), From "Brubeck parts" folder (Box-folder 82/1)
  - Backstage
    - Parts (ensemble parts), For the 1995 recording Dragonfly (Box-folder 68/3)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheets (quartet), On folder: New songs for quartet 2/9/93, originals (Box-folder 23/12)
  - Balada, Pedro Iturralde
    - Lead sheet, Laid in: manuscript letter from P. Iturralde (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Ballad
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement (Box-folder 124/5)
    - Score; parts (big band), GM arrangement for University of Miami band (Box-folder 136/4)
    - Score (tentet) (Box-folder 139/8)
    - Score; parts (tentet) (Box-folder 112/7)
    - Score (sketch), Ken Thorne arrangement (Box-folder 82/3)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement (Box-folder 35/3)
    - Lead sheets (rhythm section) (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Lead sheets (Box-folder 16/12)
  - Ballad for Thad, Simon Pilbrow
    - Lead sheets, Note in GM's music library: Some good tunes from an Australian (Box-folder 22/24)
  - Ballad of Pearly Sue
    - Lead sheets; sketches (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Lead sheet, For the Mel Tormé vocal compilation "Tentet with Tormé" (Box-folder 62/6)
  - Barbara's theme
    - Score (big band), Johnny Mandel arrangement, March 1960 (Box-folder 132/3)
  - Bark for Barksdale
    - Parts (trumpet, bass) (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheet; parts (trumpet, bass) (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Bear in the forest see Backstage
  - Because there's rain / G minor Etude
    - Lead sheets, 6 photographs of Franca Mulligan, (Italy, 1955, 1965) moved to Photographs (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Because you're my friend
    - Lead sheet, From folder: "Misc. works" some for Count Basie Band (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Begin the beguine
    - Score (big band), For Stan Kenton (Box-folder 133/5)
  - The beginning of a happy ending
    - Lead sheets, Lyrics by Marty Brill (Box-folder 18/16)
  - Beginning to see the light
    - Sketch score (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 37/2)
  - Bernie's tune, Bernie Miller
    - Score; parts (Concert Jazz Band), Bill Holman arrangement (Box-folder 123/2)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Sketch, Bill Holman arrangement (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Sketch for 4 horn ending (last 2 bars); tenor saxophone part (incomplete) (Box-folder 66/9)
    - Sketch (ending only), From "Standards" folder (Box-folder 18/19)
    - Lead sheets; parts; printed sets (2) of parts, Printed "Mulliganette" series (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Bess, Oh where's my Bess, George Gershwin
    - Parts (quartet) (Box-folder 67/2)
  - Between the devil and the deep blue sea, Harold Arlen, Ted Koehler
    - Score (sextet) (Box-folder 140/4)
  - Big city blues, Barry Manilow
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement (Box-folder 123/7)
    - Parts (guitar, bass), GM personal performance part (Box-folder 116)
    - Lead sheets; parts (piano, baritone saxophone) (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Big city life, Bob Brookmeyer
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement (Box-folder 123/6)
    - Part (baritone saxophone), GM personal performance part (Box-folder 116)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement (Box-folder 34/1)
  - Bike up the strand
    - Parts (baritone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone) (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Lead sheets (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Bilbao
    - Sketches, From "Standards" folder (Box-folder 18/19)
  - Billie's bounce, Charlie Parker
    - Lead sheet, From "Kai Winding" folder (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Birds of a feather
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Black nightgown
    - Score (big band) (Box-folder 132/4)
  - Blessed are the poor
    - Part (baritone saxophone), From "Brubeck parts" folder (Box-folder 82/1)
  - The blight of the fumblebee
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheets (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Bloomsbury
    - Score, For Dublin Radio Eire, 1970 (Box-folder 57/2)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheet; sketch (sextet) (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Blue, Barry Manilow
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Blue at the roots
    - Lead sheet, In caption: On Emarcy Records, "Mainstream" #MG 36101 (Box-folder 21/12)
  - Blue brew, Fats Navarro
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Blue Hodge, Gary McFarland
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Blue kangaroo
    - Lead sheet, On folder: GM tune/lead sheets, returned by Dave Brubeck, May 1984 (no F10C) (Box-folder 82/2)
  - Blue prelude, Gordon Jenkins; For the album Holliday with Mulligan
    - Score, Al Cohn arrangement (Box-folder 147/1)
    - Parts, Al Cohn arrangement (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Blue rondo a la Turk
    - Part (baritone saxophone), From "Brubeck parts" folder (Box-folder 82/1)
  - Blueport, Art Farmer
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Al Cohn arrangement (Box-folder 121/4)
    - Score (1992); parts (1993) (tentet) (Box-folder 138/8)
    - Parts; lead sheets, Art Farmer small band (Box-folder 65/5)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Al Cohn arrangement (Box-folder 45/3)
    - Part (rhythm section), On folder: Art Farmer, Lincoln Center '94, The art of trumpet (Box-folder 24/1)
    - Parts (tentet), From "Gig books" (Box-folder 113/4)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheets (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Blues
    - Sketch for intro, On folder: New intros in progress (Box-folder 140/7)
    - Lead sheet, Criterion Music Corp., 1960 (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Blues ending
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement (Box-folder 130/3)
  - The blues exterminator
    - Sketch; lead sheets (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Blues for brother Bird
    - Sketches; lead sheets, From folder "Misc. sextet parts" (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Blues for Mundel, Simon Pilbrow
    - Lead sheets, Note in GM's music library: Some good tunes from an Australian (Box-folder 22/24)
  - Blues going up
    - Lead sheet, Criterion Music Corp., 1960 (Box-folder 10/5)
  - The blues machine
    - Part (baritone saxophone) (Box-folder 21/12)
  - Blues march, Benny Golson
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Blues on down, Benny Golson
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Body and soul, Johnny Green
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement (Box-folder 60/2)
    - Parts (big band), George Handy arrangement for Boyd Raebuen Orchestra (Box-folder 60/2)
  - Bolero, Maurice Ravel
    - Score (orchestra) (Box-folder 81/7)